www.tvsubtitles.net
안녕하세요,미아.
Hello, Mia.
어떻게 지냈어요?
So how have you been?
조용히요
Quiet.
당신 소식 못 들었는데요
I hadn't heard from you.
내 메세지는 받았어요?
Did you get my message?
네,전화 고마워요
Yes.
Thanks for your call.
-기분은 어떤가요?
-어떻게 보여요?
- And how are you feeling?
- How do I look?
변호사의 기교죠
질문에 질문으로 대답한다?
That's a lawyer technique, right...
answer a question with a question?
바닥을 친 줄 알았어요
Well, I thought I'd hit bottom
지난번 상담때요
at the end of the last session,
근데 내리막이 있었네요
but it went downhill from there.
한가지는 알게 됐어요
I did figure something out, though.
치료 그만해야 겠어요
I'm stopping therapy.
02x31 Mia - Week Seven
In Treatment 02x31 번역: 남가주(kagy@nate.com) 재배포금지
미아 - 월요일, 오전 7:00
지금껏 해준 거 고마워요
I appreciate what you've done.
내가 힘든 케이스란 거 알아요
I know I'm a tough case.
의사 만날때 마다
기분이 더 안 좋아졌어요
But if every time
you go to the doctor,
바꿀 때란거죠
you end up feeling worse,
then it's time to move on.
전화로 할수도 있지만
와서 작별인사하고 싶었어요
And I could have called, but I wanted
to come in and say goodbye
마무리도 지을겸해서요
and wrap things up.
이해해요
I understand.
더 하라고 하지
않을건가요?
You're not going to
try to convince me to stay?
그렇게 말해주길 원해요?
Is that what you'd like me to do?
나에 대한 얘기만 한 것 같아서요
여기 저기 치료하면서요
I just assumed you'd be all over me...
"therapy this, therapy that."
붙잡아 두길 원해요?
You want me to hard-sell you
길거리에서 껍질까는 도구
파는 사람처럼?
like a guy selling you
a vegetable peeler on the street?
이런,폴
Jeez, Paul,
여기서 내가 화내면
안되는 거였죠?
don't I get to be
the angry one here?
그만 둬서 화났어요?
아니면 다른 거 때문에요?
You mad because I want to
leave or has something happened?
재미없어서 끝내고 싶다고
얼굴에 써 있네요
You look like you want
to take your ball and go home.
그럴지도요
Maybe you're right.
치료가 도움이 안 됐으면
If therapy hasn't helped,
마지막까지 붙잡아 두면
기분만 더 나빠질 거예요
the last thing I want to do
is keep you here, make you feel worse.
지난번 상담때
그랬잖아요
That's what happened
after the last session.
기분 되게 더러웠어요
I felt like shit.
집에 가서 아빠한테 전화했어요
And I went home and I called my dad,
바닥에 도달했다고 생각했으니까요
thinking that I should get
to the bottom of everything.
아빠가 오셨고
어린시절에 대해 물어봤죠
He came over
and I started asking questions
부녀가 그 얘기만 했어요
about my childhood,
all the things we'd talked about.
아빠가 등 돌리셨어요
He turned it on me...
내가 왜 옛날 얘기 꺼내서
문제를 만들었는지...
why was I creating problems,
bringing up ancient history?
아빠가 위협을
느끼셨을 것 같군요
Maybe he felt threatened.
피아노를 팔아버린게
아빠의 생각이었냐고 물어 봤어요
Especially when I asked him
if it was his idea to sell the piano.
잃어버리셨대요
He lost it...
아빠를 원망해선 안되는 거였어요
감사하게 생각해야 되는 거였죠
I shouldn't blame him;
I should be grateful;
아빠가 없었다면
난 살아 있을 수 없잖아요
I wouldn't be alive without him;
태어나는 것 부터가
불가능 했겠죠
that I was impossible
from the day I was born,
내가 태어나서
엄마가 미치신 거지만
and maybe that's why
my mother went nuts.
그럼 모두 당신 잘못이었나요?
So it was all your fault.
네, 아빤 말씀하셨어요
Yeah and he went on...
내가 남자를 찾지 못하는게
놀라운 일도 아니래요
it's no surprise
that I can't find a man;
누가 너같은 여자를
원하기나 하겠냐면서요
who would want
a woman like me?
그러시고는 밖으로 나가셨어요
And then he walked out,
다신 나랑 얘기하고
싶지 않다고 하셨죠
saying that he didn't want
to talk to me again.
안좋은 한 주를 보내서
치료를 하는 건 아니예요
So therapy isn't the only
reason you had a bad week.
당신이랑 얘기하지 않았으면
아빠를 만나지 않았을 거예요
I never would have confronted
him if I hadn't been talking to you.
그러니 이런일들 고마워요,난..
So thanks to all of this, I have...
아버지를 잃었어요
lost my father.
잃은게 아니예요
You haven't lost your father.
아직도 당신 인생에 한 부분이예요
He's still in your life,
아버지를 잃었다고 한건 당신이
과거에 가지고 있다고 생각한거죠
but you did lose the father
that you thought you had.
아버진, 어머니와의 사건을
해석하는 걸 반박하신 거예요
He didn't refute
your mother's version of events.
그냥 대답하지 않으신 거죠
He just chose not to answer.
여기서 대화해왔던 많은 부분을
확인 시켜준 거네요
And that confirms a lot of the things
that we've been talking about in here.
좋아요,폴,알겠어요
Okay, Paul, I get it.
내 아빠는 완벽하지 않아요
I didn't have the perfect dad.
당신이 맞고 내가 틀렸어요
그말이 듣고 싶었던 거예요?
You're right and I'm wrong.
Is that what you want?
오늘 상담 노트에
이렇게 적으세요
So put that in today's session notes,
which I hope you keep now...
"M이란 환자는 자기 중심적인 아버지에"
"successfully shattered patient m's
"낭만적인 이미지를 가지고 있었다
성공적으로 그 이미지를 부셔버렸다"
"romanticized image
of her narcissistic father."
사실 이렇게 쓸겁니다
Actually what I would write is
"우울증이 있는 어머니에게서
태어난 미아는"
"Mia, born to a depressed mother,
"아버질 이상형으로 생각해서
완전한 외톨이가 되진 않았다"
"idealizes her father
so as not to feel completely alone.
"마침내 이번주 아버지와 대면하면서"
"And this week,
after finally confronting him,
"그녀는 아빠의 실제 모습을
알게 되었다"
"she can see her dad
for who he really is."
"그래서 그 이미지는 부서지고 있다"
It is shattering,
"지금 아버지와의 연결을 벗어날 수 있다면"
but if you can now move beyond
that connection to your father
"다른 곳에서 사랑을 찾을
가능성이 열릴 지도 모른다"
it may open the possibility
of finding love elsewhere.
그러니까..계속 치료를 받는다면
You mean, if I stay in therapy.
하나의 방법이죠
That's one way.
유일한 방법이란 건 아니예요
It's certainly not the only way.
잘됐네요,정말 끝내려고 했어요
Good, because I really am done.
실은, 지금 가야할지도 몰라요
In fact, maybe I should get going.
그래도 돼요,물론이죠
You can, of course.
하지만 여기 왔으니
결론은 낼 수 있을거예요
But since you're here,
maybe we can at least work on...
closure.
지난 상담치료 마칠땐
비참했다는 거 알아요
I know you were unhappy
about the last time
that we ended therapy.
이번엔 더 잘 하고 싶어요
I'd like to do
a better job this time.
얼마나 걸리는데요?
How long does that take?
그건 당신한테 달렸어요
Well, that's up to you.
이번이 마지막 상담이라면
남은 시간을 이용할 거예요
If this is your last session,
we'll use the time that's left.
난 솔직해 질테니
당신도 솔직하게 말해줘요
And I'll be honest, you be honest.
어때요?
How's that?
좋아요,마지막 상담이니..
Okay, last session.
뭐 할까요?
What do we do?
아버지가 떠나신뒤
어땠는지 말해줄래요?
You haven't told me what
happened after your father left.
그 얘기가 결론인가요?
That's how we do closure?
세이지향 같은 거나
태우면 안돼요?
Couldn't we just burn
some sage or something?
당신 유머가 참 좋아요,미아
I enjoy your humor a lot, Mia.
때론 그런식으로
But sometimes I feel
it's a way of...
회피하는 거라
느끼곤 하지만요
It's a way of hiding.
아빠가 떠나신 후
After dad left,
일주일 내내 많은 시간
집에서 있었어요
I pretty much stayed home all week
침대에서요
in bed.
안좋게 들릴 거란 건 알지만
지금 여기 왔으니
And I know that sounds bad,
but I'm here now,
극복한거죠
so I got through it.
침대에서 나오지 않았다고요?
Did you get out of bed at all?
화장실 돌아다니고
부엌도 돌아다니고
Bathroom trips, kitchen trips.
배달 온거 확인하러
문에 가보고
I answered the door for deliveries.
다른 사람과는 얘기하지 않았나요?
Did you talk to anybody?
믿음직한 조수 '헨리'랑요
My trusty assistant Henry,
와볼거라고 위협하고
나한테 요리해 주던데요
who threatened to come over
and cook for me.
-나한텐 전화하고 싶진 않았나요?
-무슨 말을 했을것 같아요?
- You didn't want to call me?
- What would I have said...
"커버 밑에 숨어있는 중이예요"
"거실이 두렵거든요? "
"I'm under the covers 'cause
I'm afraid of the living room"?
그렇게 느꼈다면, 그랬겠죠
If that's how you felt, then yes.
-좀 절망적이라고 생각해요?
-자살 안해요,걱정 말아요
Have you been feeling
a little hopeless?
I'm not suicidal, Paul, don't worry.
나 좀 강해요
I am pretty tough.
강하기 때문에 이런 일을
혼자 겪어야 한다는 거예요?
Does being tough mean you have to
suffer through things like this alone?
그냥 침대가 안전하다고 느꼈어요
I just felt like the bed was safe
또 거실은
무서웠어요
and the living room
was scary.
그래서 침대에 있었군요
So you took to bed
당신 어머니처럼
like your mother did.
엄만 산후 우울증이 있었어요
내 변명은 뭐죠? 유산 우울증?
She had post-partum.
What's my excuse... post-non-partum?
난 당신이 겪은 일들
하찮게 보지 않아요,미아
I wouldn't belittle what
you've been through, Mia.
아이를 원했잖아요
You wanted a child.
아이를 가졌다고 생각했었고요
You thought you were having one.
유산은 고통스런 거예요
That's a painful loss.
더군다나 당신은 상처 받고 있었고
아버질 몹시 필요로 했지만
And on top of that,
when you were vulnerable
and need your father the most,
아버진 당신 옆에 계시지 않았어요
he wasn't there for you,
똑같은 식으로 어머니가
침대에만 계셨을때도
maybe the same way
he wasn't there for your mother
어버진 어머니 곁에
계시지 않았을거예요
when she couldn't get out of bed.
이래서 내가 치료를
그만 두려는 거예요
This is exactly why
I'm done with therapy.
대화할때 마다 매번 난..
Every time we talk, I feel like
하루를 무사히 보내기 위해
상담사를 만나는 느낌이예요
I need to see a therapist
just to get through the day.
좋아요,알겠어요
Okay, I hear you.
-더이상 엄마,아빠 얘긴 안 할께요
-이런식으로 결론 내리는 거예요?
- No more dad. No more mom.
- Is this how closure works?
내 가족사는 끔찍했다는 걸
알려주고 그 다음은..
You remind me
of my miserable family life,
내 인생 사랑 얘기하고
다음은 뭔가요? 지구 온난화?
and then my love life, and then what?
Global warming?
그럼 무슨 얘기 해 볼까요?
So what would you
like to talk about?
앵무새 한마리 구할 거예요
I was thinking about
getting a parrot
애완 동물로
as a pet,
남자 친구나
상담치료사를 대신할
instead of a boyfriend
or a therapist.
이름을 폴이라고
지을 수도 있겠네요
I could name it paul
이런 말을 가르칠 수 있구요
and I could teach it
to say things like,
"무슨 얘기 하고 싶어요?"
"what would you like to talk about?"
아니면
"난 가요? 당신 아버진가요?
Or "is it me or is it your father?"
그 다음엔 앵무새가 대략 80년을
산다는 걸 알게 되겠죠
But then I found out
that parrots live for about 80 years.
난 그렇게 오래 누군가와 함께
할 수 없다는 것도 알게 되고요
And I don't think I could
stand anybody for that long.
그만 두더라도
날 옆에 두고 싶은 거군요
So you want to go,
but you also want to keep me around,
내 목소리라도요
or at least you want
to keep my voice.
이봐요,폴
Look, paul,
당신을 좋아해요
I like you
한 사람으로서
I like you as a person.
확실하단 뜻이예요
I mean, that's pretty obvious.
우리가 친구라면
매우 좋을거예요
If we were friends,
that would be great.
하지만 그럴 수 없죠
But we're not.
당신이 친구가 될 거라고
상상하진 않아요
And I don't imagine you're
going to become my friend.
규정에 반하는 거니까요
That's against the rules.
물론,내 이름이 로라면
다르겠지만요
Unless, of course,
my name were laura.
-아직도 그 일 땜에 화 나 있군요
-그냥 화를 잘내는 사람이예요
- You're still angry about that.
- Maybe I'm just an angry person
또, 현재 내 모습을
받아들여야만 하구요
and I should just accept
myself for who I am.
-아뇨,특히 나한테 화나 있어요
-아뇨,좋아한다고 했잖아요
- No, you're specifically angry at me.
- No, I said I like you.
그리고 날 상담사가 아닌
친구로서 원하고요
And you want me as a friend
but not as a therapist.
해 줄 수 없는 걸 원하는군요
You want what I can't give you.
딴 새로운 얘기는요?
What else is new?
문제는 '왜 치료를 그만두는가'가 아니라
'왜 처음 위치로 되돌아 갔는가' 일지 몰라요
Maybe the question isn't
why you're leaving, mia,
but why you came back
in the first place.
내가 치료 과실로 소송
당했다는 거 알잖아요
You clearly knew that I was
being sued for malpractice. And
당신은 20년전에 내가 당신한테
잘못했다고 생각하고 있어요
you believed that I had
failed you 20 years ago.
그때 생각해 보죠
어떤 선택을 하라고 했었죠?
Think about it.
What kind of choice was that?
별로 좋지는 않았어요
It wasn't a really good one.
그게 완벽한 건지도 모르죠
Or maybe it was perfect,
당신은 인생에서 남자를
고르는 것과 같은 식으로
if you were trying to choose
a therapist in the same way that
상담사를 고르잖아요
you choose the men in your life
실망시킬지도 모르는
어떤 남자를 찾으면서
look for someone who's
likely to let you down,
아니다 싶을 땐 벗어나기 위해
모든 짓을 하겠죠
do everything you can
to drive him away,
실망시킨거에 대해
그사람에게 분노하잖아요
and when he fails you,
which he must inevitably,
then you get to rage against him.
잘 하셨네요
Nicely done.
아빠 얘기 없이
아버지 얘기로 돌아왔네요
You've even doubled back to dad,
without having to mention him.
이봐요,미아, 물론
그만하고 싶으면 가도 돼요
Look, mia,
of course you're free to leave
therapy,
하지만 내 생각엔..
꼬인 줄을 풀지 않으면
but my guess is,
until you untangle those
crossed wires,
다음 남자,다른 남자
또 다른 남자를 만나도
the next man, and the one after that,
and the one after that
그 사람들한테 또 실망할 거예요
they're going to disappoint you too.
그게 내 인생 패턴 인가요?
That's my lifelong pattern
내가...
because I've been
나쁜 아빠에 얽매여 있어서요?
too attached to bad dad?
20년전에 왜 말하지 않았나요?
Why didn't you tell
me this 20 years ago?
-그러니까..제기랄 왜?
-내 잘못이란 건가요?
- I mean, what the fuck?
- Are you saying it's my fault?
예전에 알았으면
버젓한 삶을 살았을지도 모르죠
Maybe I would have had a decent
life if I had known that.
지금은 좀 늦었잖아요
It's a little late now.
그당시 그렇게 말했다면
내말을 들었을까요?
Would you have even heard me
if I'd said it that back then?
그래서 당신은 기다렸다는 거예요?
So you waited?
당신이 기다리고 있는 동안
난 폐경기에 접어들고요? 좋네요
And while you waited,
I hit perimenopause? Great.
-당신은 또 그러고 있어요,미아
-뭘요?
- You're doing it again, mia.
- What?
필요로 했을때 그걸 주지 않았다고
날 원망하고 있잖아요
Blaming me for not giving you
what you need when you needed it.
이제 알겠네요
Now I get it
그러니까...결론이란게
모두다 내 잘못이란 거군요
closure is you telling
me that it's all my fault
그리고는 강요하는 거예요?
and that I set you up.
이런 식으로 우리 둘다
원하는 걸 얻었네요
That way we can both
have what we want-
난 당신에게 화내고
당신은 상담을 끝낼수 있고요
I can be mad at you,
and you can be done with me.
좋아요,그럼 나갈때 이렇게 말해야겠군요
'난 이제야 안심이 되네요"
Here's where you tell me how relieved
I'll be when you walk out the door.
그다음엔 내가 이렇게
말한다는 거죠
And then you're going to say
'당신은 내목에 들이댄 칼 같아요'
'그만한다니 이제 기분이 좋네요'
that you're like a knife in my neck,
that it'll feel good when you're gone.
그런다는 거죠? 안그래요?
That how it goes, isn't it?
보세요,이런말은
당신이 전문이잖아요
See, this is your specialty, ia.
그런 패턴을 반복하고 싶으면
좋아요,하세요
And if you want to keep repeating
that pattern, that's fine. Go ahead.
하지만 인생에서
변화를 원하다면
But if you want to make
a change in your life,
치료를 계속 받으라고
권고하는 거예요
I suggest that you stay in therapy.
나한테 받지 않아도 괜찮아요
And it doesn't even
need to be with me.
당신 패턴 얘기 할 수 있을까요?
Can we talk about your patterns?
내 패턴이요?
My patterns?
예를 들면..
Like what?
소파위에 여자를 눕히는
기분 어땠나요?
How you like to have
a woman on the couch
당신을 사랑하고
있는 사람을요
who thinks she's in love with you,
그래 좋았나요?
how you get off on that.
좋았냐고요?
Get off on it?
날 어떻게 보는지
알고 있어요
I've seen how you look at me.
당신은 무관심한 표정을 아주 잘 지었어요
하지만 언제 그게 먹혀드는지 난 알아요
You hold up that
neutral face pretty well,
but I see when it slips
내 목을 보고 있잖아요
and you're looking at my neck
내 다리
or my legs
아니면 내 가슴
어떨지 궁금해 하면서요
or my breasts and you're
wondering what it would be like.
제발요, 폴
솔직해 지자고 했잖아요
Come on, paul,
you said you'd be honest.
연극 그만하는 거 어때요?
How about you drop the act?
보너스 삭감된 헤지펀드일 하는
환자들처럼 날 가지고 싶잖아요
You know you'd rather have
me as a patient ten some
hedge fund guy whose
bonus has been reduced.
우리 사이에 환상이
없었다고 말하지 말아요
Don't tell me you haven't
had fantasies about us.
그런 여자들 침대에서
많이 섹시하죠?
Crazy chicks are hot in bed, right?
왜 그래요?
내가 불편하게 해요?
What's the matter?
Am I making you uncomfortable?
그냥 바로 지금
침대로 가서 섹스할까요?
Why don't we just go in
the bedroom right now and fuck?
부엌 카운터는 어때요?
Or how about on the kitchen counter?
로라와 안했다는건 잘 알아요
I bet you never did that with laura.
그럼 내 치료로
얻은 건 없어서
So there's nothing to
be learned from therapy,
그냥 가서 섹스하자고요?
그거예요?
so let's just go fuck? Is that it?
적어도 둘다 끔찍한 일상에서
벗어나서 안도감은 얻잖아요
At least we'd get some relief
from our miserable lives.
당신은 그런식으로
결론을 짓나요?
So that's your version of closure?
말도 안되는 얘기가 도움되는 것처럼
가식떠는 거 보단 기분은 더 좋아지잖아요
It would make us feel better,
instead of pretending that this
talking nonsense actually helps.
나때문에 규정을 깨면
어떻게 되는데요?
What would it be like if you
broke all the rules for me?
내가 하고 싶다고
생각하는 거예요?
You mean if I said
yes?
하고 싶어요?
So you want to?
하고 싶다면요?
What if I do?
어떻게 될까요?
What would happen?
무슨 말이예요?
What are you saying?
결국 당신이 특별하다는
충만감을 느끼게 될까요?
Would you finally
feel special enough?
그래서 모든 걸 바로잡고
모든 걸 얻게 될까요?
Would it fix everything,
to win like that?
아니면 선을 넘어서
날 원망하게 될까요?
Or would you just blame
me for crossing the line?
당신, 변호사잖아요,제길!
You're a lawyer, for chrissake.
어떨지 알잖아요
You know what it would mean.
난 부적절한 치료로
유죄가 된다고요
Then I would be truly
guilty of malpractice.
당신이 그런 의사들
대변하는 거잖아요
You've probably represented
doctors like that.
당신 치료는 확실히
그만둘 수 있겠군요
Hell of a way to get out of therapy,
I have to say
-난 당신의 의뢰인이 되고요
-그렇게 하려는게 아니예요
- turn me into one of your clients.
- That's not what I'm doing.
아니라고요?
내가 당신을 필요로 할텐데요
Isn't it? Then I would need you.
당신 관리하에 있겠죠
You would be in control.
당신은 더 수월해지고
And that would be much
more comfortable for you,
사무실에서 다시 날 갖게 되니까요
to have me back in your office.
어쩌면
Maybe
그렇게 하려는 건지도 모르죠
maybe that's why you really do it.
뭘요?
What?
- 당신 일로 만들려고요
- 화제를 돌리네요
- Your job.
- You're changing the topic.
당신 겁 먹고 있죠?
Are you getting scared?
당신을 도와주려는 거예요
내 일이니까요
I'm trying to help you.
That's my job.
당신 일은 뭐죠? 미아
매일 어떤 일을 하나요?
What's yours, mia?
What do you do at work every day?
다른 사람처럼
뭘하는지 알잖아요
You know as well
as anyone what I do.
당신 사건 어떻게
되가고 있어요?
How is your case going?
지난 주에 출근 못했는데
심리 열릴 거 아니었나요?
I wasn't in last week.
Don't you have a hearing coming up?
그럴거라 더군요
So they tell me.
그래요,맞아요
지난 주에 출근 안했죠
But you're right, you
weren't in last week.
출근 했다면
어떤 사건 맡고 있었을까요?
If you had gone in, what cases
would you have been working on?
재판은 없었으니
새 의뢰인 만나려고 했겠죠
No trials.
I was supposed to meet a new client
9살 아이를 오진해서
죽이다시피 했거든요
a pediatrician who
misdiagnosed some nine-year-old kid,
almost killed him.
침대에만 있을만 하군요
No wonder you stayed in bed.
난 내 의뢰인을
판단하지 않아요,폴
I don't judge my clients, paul.
보호하죠
I protect them.
권력을 가진 사람의 약점과 결백을
보호하지 못한게 몇번이나 되죠?
And how many of
your clients are powerful men
who fail to protect
the vulnerable and the innocent?
의뢰인들은 고소당할 사람이지만,폴
They're being sued, paul,
당신과 똑같이
유죄를 뜻하는 건 아니예요
just like you.
That doesn't mean they're guilty.
변호사 한지는 얼마나 됐죠?
And how long have
you been doing that?
17년이요
17 years.
병가 낸다고
전화 몇번 했나요?
How often do you call in sick?
로펌 다닌 후에요?
Since I got there?
5일,4일
Five days, four.
17년 동안?
In 17 years?
휴가 포함해서요?
And vacations?
쓰지 않으면
당신도 계속 일하잖아요
You don't lose the weeks
if you don't take them.
알겠어요,근데 지난주는..
I see. But last week,
아버지를 만난후엔
출근하지 않았네요
after confronting your father,
you didn't go in.
당신 말처럼, 우울했거든요
According to you, I was depressed.
그랬을 거지만
I think you were.
우연이라 생각하지 않아요
But I don't think it's a coincidence
직무유기해서 아이에게 위해를 가한
사람을 변호하고 싶지 않은 거였잖아요
that suddenly you didn't want to
defend somebody whose negligence
had harmed a child.
그 사람들이 모두 유죄는
아니라고 했지만
Look, I'm not saying
they're all guilty,
의뢰인을 변호하러
당신이 법정에 설 때마다
but every time you stand in
that courtroom to defend a client,
사실, 다른사람에게서 아버질
변호하고 있었던 거라 생각되네요
I think you're actually defending
your father to everybody,
특히 자신에게서요
especially yourself.
젠장
Shit.
그걸 안지 얼마나 됐어요?
How long have you known that one?
일리 있나요?
Does it make sense to you?
연관 짓지 못했네요
I never made the connexion...
그런 생각 해보지도 못했구요
and now I'm stuck with it.
전엔 가진 건 없는 줄 알았는데
지금은 그보다도 못하네요
I felt like I had nothing before.
Now I have less than nothing.
겁 나는 거 알아요
I know it feels scary
좋은 일 일지도 몰라요
but maybe that's a good thing.
아무것도 가지지 못한게
좋은 일이라고요?
It's a good thing
that I have nothing?
고맙네요
Thank you.
인생에서 계속 잘못된 선택만 했단걸
알게 해줘서 고마워요
Thank you. You've helped me
to realize that I've made
poor choice after poor choice
my whole life.
하지만 이걸 알아야 해요,미아
But you also have to realize, Mia,
당신은 인생에서 중요한
기로에 있는거예요
that you're at a critical juncture
in your life,
지금 자각하고 있구요
that now you do have
the self-knowledge
다른 선택, 더 좋은 선택을 할 수 있다는..
to make different, better choices.
폴리애나 같은 소리 하지 말아요
[폴리애나-1913년 소설 '폴리애나'의 낙천적 성격의 주인공]
Don't give me any of this
Pollyanna shit.
정말로 변화 하려는 때는
가장 힘든 것과 싸우는 시기예요
And sometimes when you're
on the verge of real change,
that's when you fight the hardest.
당신이 첫날 다시 왔을때
당신에게 묻고 싶었어요
When you first came back
I tried to ask you
아버지와 당신의 연관성에 대해서요
about your connection to your father
당신은 말도 꺼내지 못하게 했고
아버지에 대해 알길 원치 않았어요
and you shut me down. You didn't want
to know anything about it.
지난 주에 당신은 아버질 만났잖아요
This past week you confronted him.
맞아요, 그래 얼마나 잘 됐는지 보세요
Yeah, look how well that worked out.
쉬운일이라고 말하려는 게 아니예요
하지만 가치있어요
I'm not saying it was easy.
But maybe it's worth it.
드디어 눈가리게를 벗어 버렸잖아요
To finally take off the blinders,
보이는 게 맘에 들지 않지만
대안 있어요?
even if you don't like what you see.
Because what is the alternative?
다시 눈가리게를 쓰고
어둠속을 방황할 거예요?
Put them back on again
and wander around in the darkness?
-그걸 벗겨야 했나요?
-내가 한 게 아니예요, 당신이 벗은거죠
Did you have to take them off?
I didn't do it. You did.
무슨 생각해요?
What are you thinking?
아무것도요
Nothing.
남은 인생,난 뭘 해야 하죠?
What am I going to do
with the rest of my life?
내가...
I want...
2달전에 여기 왔을때 바랬던 건
the same things I wanted
when I came here two months ago...
남자, 가정, 가족이예요
a man, a home, a family.
그런 거 가질 수 있을거
같지 않네요
I'm no closer to getting them.
정말 결혼하면
모든게 더 좋아질 것 같나요?
Do you really think that getting married
is going to make it all better?
얼마나 많은 결혼한 사람들과 많은 부모들이
공허감을 느끼는지 알고 있어요?
Do you have any idea
of how many married people,
how many parents feel
as empty as you do?
당신에게 묻죠
Let me ask you...
진정한 행복을 마지막으로
느낀게 언젠가요?
when was the last time
you felt real happiness?
임신했다고 생각한 몇주전이요
A couple weeks ago when I thought
that I was pregnant.
당신은 왜 기분이 좋았나요?
And what about
that made you feel good?
나 때문만은 아니었어요
인생에 의미가 있었다는 거 였죠
That it wasn't just me,
that my life had meaning,
다른 사람과 함께
있었다는 거였죠,항상
that there would be
this other person, always.
행복이 아이나 남편 때문이 아니라고
생각해 본 적 있어요? 미아
Have you ever considered that maybe
it's not about a child, Mia,
or a husband?
그건 당신 머리속에 있는
그냥 그림일지도 몰라요
Maybe that's just a picture
in your head
당신 가족, 당신 친구들
문화속에서 나온 그림
from your family, from your friends,
from the culture.
충만하고 만족스런 인생을 살기 위해
모두가 그런 그림이 필요한 건 아니예요
Not everyone needs that
to live a full and contented life.
정말로 당신이 원하는 건,미아
사람들과의 유대감일지 몰라요
Maybe what you really want, Mia,
is to feel connected,
진심으로 누군가나
authentically connected
어떤것과 상호간에 연결하는 거요
to somebody or something else.
우리둘다 내가 그런거
없다는 건 알잖아요
And we both know
that I can't have that.
-왜 없어요?
-진실한 유대감? 내가요?
- Why not?
- An authentic connection? Me?
-가져본적 없어요, 그럴 수도 없고요
-확실해요?
- I've never had that. I'm incapable.
- Are you sure?
여기선 어때요?
What about in here?
농담해요?
Are you kidding me?
여기서 엉망된다고요
I'm a mess in here.
난 당신 공격하고 흠잡고
유혹이나 하는데요
I attack you. I've dumped on you.
I've tried to seduce you.
-부서진 열차 같잖아요
-좋아요, 때론 그렇게 행동했죠
- I've been a train wreck.
- Okay, at times you have acted out.
하지만 그러지 않았다면
우리가 어떻게 진단할 수 있었겠어요?
But if you hadn't,
how could we examine it?
그건 당신이 필요로하는 걸 알기위해
우리 둘이 소통하는 방법이었어요
It's been your way of communicating
to both of us what you need.
당신은 또 솔직했잖아요
You've also been honest,
인정 많았고
자신을 공격받도록 했어요
caring.
You've made yourself vulnerable.
진실한 모습을
나에게 보여줬어요
You've shown me who you really are.
회피하지도 않았고
And you haven't walked away.
아직까진요
Yet.
변화를 원한다는 걸
우리 둘 다 알잖아요
We both know
that you really want to change.
그래서 계속 여기 오는 거 잖아요
That's the real reason
you keep coming back.
네,물론 당신은 인생에서
친근감을 원하고 있어요
Yes, of course you want
intimacy in your life.
알아요...
And I know...
당신이 친근해 질 수 있다는 걸 알아요
I know that you're capable of that.
-우린 벌써 그렇잖아요
-언제요? 말해봐요
- Because we've had it.
- When? Name one time.
지금
바로 지금
Now.
Right now.
시간 됐죠?
Our time is up, right?
고마워요, 폴
Thank you, Paul.
좋은 상담이었어요
It was a good session.
잘가요, 미아
Goodbye, Mia.
그럼..
So...
다음 주에 볼 수 있을 거 같네요
I guess I'll see you next week.
좋죠?
좋아요
여기 있을께요
I'll be here.